Guide to the Roy J. Bostock papers, 1976-2002 and undated RL.11621
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roy J. Bostock papers
1976-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bostock, Roy J.
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11621
1.5 Linear Feet
Advertising executive and former Chairman of D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles agency, headquartered in New York. Collection includes correspondence, corporate reports, clippings, speeches and videocassettes. Companies represented include Benton & Bowles, D'Arcy MacManus Masius, D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles, Burger King, Duke University, Fuqua School of Business, General Motors, Hardee's, Kal Kan and Procter & Gamble. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Speeches; Speeches by Others; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive and former Chairman of D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles agency, headquartered in New York.
Graduated Duke University 1962, Harvard MBA; Started Benton & Bowles 1964. DMB&B: President 1985; CEO and Chairman 1990-1996. Chairman MacManus Group 1996-2000. Chairman B/Com3 2000-2002. Chairman Yahoo! Inc. 2008-2012.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Roy J. Bostock papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles archives
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation vertical files
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, corporate reports, clippings, speeches and videocassettes. Companies represented include Benton & Bowles, D'Arcy MacManus Masius, D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles, Burger King, Duke University, Fuqua School of Business, General Motors, Hardee's, Kal Kan and Procter & Gamble. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Advertising executives; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Benton & Bowles; D'Arcy MacManus Masius; D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles; Burger King Corporation; Duke University; Fuqua School of Business (Duke University); General Motors Corporation; Hardee's Food Systems; Procter & Gamble Company
- General Files, 1985-1999 and undated; 1
  - Advertising Tax Coalition, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Agency Magazine feature on John O'Toole (Foote cone & Belding, AAAA Chairman), 1994 (Box 1)
  - Anecdote from McCann Erickson, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Cartoons on business management, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with William O'Barr (Duke University), 1985 (Box 1)
  - DMB&B annual report, 1991 (Box 1)
  - King Arthur/Excalibur legend, undated (Box 1)
  - MacManus Group annual report, 1996 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - MacManus Group prospectus on proposed merger with Leo Group, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Press on Burger King, Maxwell House accounts, 1989 (Box 1)
- Speeches, 1976-2002 and undated; 2
  - 8 myths about advertising, 1988 (Box 1)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies) annual meeting, 1993 (Box 1)
  - AAAA Chairman's address--Welcome to the revolution, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Accountability in action (ANA conference), 1993 (Box 1)
  - Advertiser-agency conflicts (Advertiser magazine), 1993 (Box 1)
  - Advertising awards dinner, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Agency compensation and fee arrangements, undated (Box 1)
  - B&B (Benton & Bowles) annual international meeting, 1979 (Box 1)
  - B&B stockholders meeting, 1984 (Box 1)
  - B&B/USA organization, circa 1985 (Box 1)
  - Big brands: Is the thrill gone?, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Briefing for New York public affairs and contributions officers, undated (Box 1)
  - Burger King, circa 1989 (Box 1)
  - Committee for Economic Development--Early education breakfast, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Cultural and economic impact of advertising on society: The U.S. as model, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Danger: High fever--Measuring the health of your agency, 1978 (Box 1)
  - DMB&B international strategic process video (introduction), 1989 (Box 1)
  - Duke University MBA Club symposium, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Duke University presentation, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Duke University remarks, Advertising in America Conference, undated (Box 1)
  - Food and Drug Administration (FDA) impact on marketing, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Fuqua School of Business--Commencement address, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Fuqua School of Business--First year marketing class, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Fuqua School of Business--MBA speech, 2002 (Box 1)
  - General Foods new hire orientation, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Hardee's, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Imperative for the 1990s: Advertising research and planning, 1993 (Box 2)
  - International advertising in the mid-70s, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Jack Bowen 25th anniversary, undated (Box 2)
  - Kal Kan, undated (Box 2)
  - Keys to the succesful introduction of new products in the food industry, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Mars candy, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Maximizing the power of advertising and other lessons still in the making, 1978 (Box 2)
  - MBA presentation, undated (Box 2)
  - Medicus Group--Interactive media and the healthcare industry, 1995 (Box 2)
  - New era of advertising (AAAA), 1995 (Box 2)
  - Nineteen ninety three, undated (Box 2)
  - Pari Mutuel Urbain, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Procter & Gamble (P&G) account management personnel, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Putting learning first (Harvard), 1995 (Box 2)
  - Radio: Max creativity with multi options, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Sports management seminar (Notre Dame), 1990 (Box 2)
  - The will to manage, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled, on change in the advertising/marketing business, undated (Box 2)
  - Vick Division meeting (on launching new products), 1981 (Box 2)
  - What top management looks for to fill account management jobs, 1976 (Box 2)
- Speeches by Others, 1986-1995 and undated; 3
  - Alex Kroll--AAAA, 1992 (Box 2)
  - C.K. Pralahad and Gary Hamel--The core competencies of the corporation, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Hugo Powell (Labatt)--Canadian Congress of Advertising, undated (Box 2)
  - John Smale (General Motors)--Canadian Congress of Advertising, 1995 (Box 2)
  - John Smale (General Motors)--Why do great companies lose their leadership?, 1993 (Box 2)
  - John Smith (General Motors)--Business Statesman Award acceptance remarks, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Philip Geier (Interpublic)--Advocacy for advertising, 1992 (Box 2)
  - R.R. Nicolosi--Have fun doing it (advertising copy and development), 1986 (Box 2)
  - William Young--Wine Marketing Symposium, 1986 (Box 2)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1990-2002 and undated; 4
  - Financial News Network (FNN) Roy Bostoc interview, 1990 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-001)
  - Imperative for the 1990s: Advertising research and planning, 1993 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-002)
  - Mars presentation, 1996 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-003)
    Scope and Contents
    Seeds of change; Uncle Ben: Deliveries, Picky; Whiskas: Making Friends, Mookie and Pookie
  - Protection master, undated (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-004)
  - Roy Bostock tribute to Bob Wehling--Master, undated (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-005)
  - Roy Bostock tribute to Bob Wehling--Dub, undated (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-006)
  - Sports management seminar, 1990 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-Umatic-007)
    Sea World: 4:30 Show; Crest: Sparkles; Daily Express: London; Southwestern Bell: Babysitter; Budweiser: Fountain of youth; Bud Bowl II 4th quarter; Dow: Angel Flight; Sony: Monkey; Life: Welcome to L.A.; Twix: Level-headed; Bahamas anthem
  - Financial News Network (FNN) Roy Bostoc interview, 1990 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-VHS-001)
  - John Smale bio video Cincinnati version, 2002 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11621-VHS-002)